owens.edu 2019-04-16

# Privacy Statement, Owens Community College - Owens Community College

* * *

## Overview

Thank you for visiting the Owens Community College website and reviewing our privacy statement. Owens Community College does not collect personal information about visitors to our website unless you choose to provide that information to us. Owens Community College does not sell, exchange or release information gathered from your visit to our web site to parties outside the College without your consent. Once we obtain your consent, we consider it valid until revoked by you.

## Information Collected and Stored Automatically

If you visit our website, we automatically gather and store the following information about your visit so that we can track the use of our website in order to make improvements. This information is stored and used in the aggregate only, and is not used to contact you personally:

  * The IP address from which you access our website.
  * The name of the domain from which you access the Internet (for example, Verizon, Roadrunner, Comcast, SBC / AT&T). 
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our website.
  * The date and time you access our site.
  * The pages, files, documents and links that you visit.
  * The Internet address of the website from which you linked to this website.

## Cookies

In addition to information collected automatically, we may also collect cookies, which are small pieces of information sent to your browser by a website that you visit. Cookies are used to track usage patterns, traffic trends and customer behavior, as well as to record other information from the website. When you register on the website, cookies also allow us to save information so that you will not have to re-enter it the next time you visit. Many content adjustments and customer service improvements are made based on the data derived from cookies. Information that we collect from cookies will not be used to create profiles of users and only will be used in aggregate form.

You may set your browser to refuse cookies from any website that you visit. If you so choose, you may still gain access to most of the College's website, but you may not be able to take advantage of some of the interactive elements offered.

## If You Send us Personal Information

The Owens Community College website will only collect personal information which you knowingly and voluntarily provide by, for example, sending emails, completing membership forms, registering for classes, events, or other programs, responding to surveys or ordering merchandise. If you provide us with personal information, we will normally respond to your inquiry, request or order. We may also contact you to provide information about College activities, programs, membership and development opportunities and special events that may interest you.

Owens Community College will only share information about you to other parties when one or more of the following conditions apply:

  * We have your consent to share the information.
  * We need to share your information to provide the service or product you requested.
  * We need to send your information to companies who work on behalf of Owens Community College to provide a service or product to you.
  * We need to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or any other legal process.
  * We find it necessary to protect and defend the legal rights and/or property of Owens Community College.

Student directory information may be released without the student’s written consent. Directory information includes: name, address, email address, I.D., photo, telephone number, date and place of birth, major field of study, participation in Owens Community College activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance at Owens Community College, degrees, certificates and awards received, and the most recent previous educational institution attended. If you do not want your directory information released, you must [complete this form](https://www.owens.edu/records/withhold.pdf) requesting it not be released and file the form with the Records Office. 

## Linking

Within the website there are links to non-Owens websites. When you link to third party websites, you leave our website and no longer will be subject to our privacy policy. Owens Community College is not responsible for the privacy practices nor the content of non-Owens websites, and such link is not intended to be an endorsement of the non-Owens website or its content.

## Comments

Owens Community College is a large organization with many people sharing responsibility for the content of our website. If you have questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us via email at [webinfo@owens.edu](mailto:webinfo@owens.edu).
